In the next few videos,
在下面的几个视频中
we'll use a dataset that contains questions from the tech exchange site.
我们要使用技术交流论坛的数据集 这个数据集包括了很多在这个论坛上被大家讨论的问题
Each question has an ID, title field,
每个问题都包含 ID 、 标题字段
a body field describing the content of the question and a list of tags.
和问题的内容字段以及问题的标签字段
We will use this dataset to create some features,
我们会使用这个数据集创建一些特征
and train various machine learning models.
并训练各种机器学习模型
I should mention though,
注意
that the purpose of these examples is not to actually find the best features,
这些例子的目的不是教你找最好的特征
or to train the most accurate models.
或是训练最准确的模型
I'll show you some generic techniques that you can leverage when you
我会向你展示一些通用技术
need to compute features and green walls on large data sets.
以便你在大型数据集上计算特征和模型
Some of these cost limpets were heavily inspired by the spiral documentation.
课程中的许多例子都深受 Spark 文档的启发
I would encourage you,
我希望
whenever you are watching these videos to
你正在观看这些视频时
open up the documentation and checkout these parts,
能打开官方文档去看看这些部分的内容
you will find a lot more information about what's available in Sparks ML library.
你在 Spark ML 库里将找到更多相关信息
First, let me import a few functions via need layer,
首先 我先导入一些待会儿要用的函数
then I just specified the S3 bucket.
然后把数据在
But the data currently assigns,
S3 bucket 中存储的路径写好
the file is called, "Train_onetag_small.jason."
该文件名为 “ Train_onetag_small.jason ”
This is a smaller sample of this file with about a 100,000 rows.
这是文件中的一个小样本 大约有 100,000 行
I decided to use the smaller dataset to cut
我用小数据集的原因是
down the time we will need to compute things in this video,
减少在视频里的计算时间
but everything I show here should work on the bigger dataset as well.
不过我在这里展示的东西也适用于更大的数据集
The records of these datasets are stored in json format.
这个数据集以 json 格式存储的
So, we can use the read.json method to load the dataset into a Spark DataFrame called df.
所以 我们可以使用 read.json 方法将数据集加载到名为 df 的 Spark DataFrame 中
We have our DataFrame,
DataFrame 已经创建好了
you can see the different columns.
你可以看到不同的列
There's body, ID, tags, title and oneTag.
问题内容、 ID 、 标签 、 标题 和oneTag
If we look at the head of the DataFrame,
如果我们看一下 DataFrame 的头行
the first question is about,
头行的问题是
"How to check if an uploaded file is an image without mime type",
“ 如何检查上传的文件是否是没有 mime 类型的图像”
it has a few tags,
它有几个标签
php image-processing, file-upload, upload and mime-types.
php图像处理，文件上传，上传和 mime 类型
As a first step, we will create a few features.
第一步 我们要创建一些特征
Let's start with the lengths of the description of the question.
我们先从问题描述的长度开始
To compute this, first you need to tokenize the text to break it into words,
要计算这个 首先你要把文本分解为单词
we can use the ML libraries regexTokenizer,
我们可以使用 ML 库 里的 regexTokenizer
to turn the body into all lowercase words where they only keep diverge themselves,
它只保留文本里的单词并把所有字母改成小写
but no other punctuation or special characters.
其他标点符号或特殊字符都会被去掉
This pattern parameter describes this behavior.
这个模式里的参数就是这个意思
So, we took the column body and created a column coordinates.
我们通过 body 列创建了一个新列 叫做 words
If you look at the first record,
你看第一行
we can see that we have a new field indeed codewords,
确实有一个新的字段 words 被创建了
and it is just a list of the words we se in the questions body.
它包含了问题主体中的所有单词
In certain cases, for example I'd,
某些情况下 例如 I’d
pre-created i and d separately since we omitted all the punctuations.
因为我们把所有的标点符号去掉了 所以 i 和 d 就分开了
Now, we can write a user-defined function to compute the lengths of this list,
现在 我们可以写个自定义函数来计算这个列表的长度
and we can just call this column body_length,
我们把这列叫做为 body_length
we need to use an underscore instead of a dash.
我们要用下划线而不是破折号
So, we created this user-defined function and we will adjust,
我们创建了这个自定义函数后 接下来我们会
add a column called,
把这个函数用在 dataframe 中的 words 列上
"BodyLength", by applying this function to the words-column in our data frame.
从而创造出一个名为 “BodyLength" 的列
Let's take a look at third,
我们来看一下
as you can see it,
正如你所看到的
it's 83 in this particular first example.
第一行的问题内容的长度是83
We can also use the Python regex_library and write some regex_patterns, for example,
我们也可以使用 Python regex 库写一些正则表达式
we can check how many paragraphs or links we have in the body.
来看看内容中有多少段落或链接
We can use the paragraph and link closing tags as a proxy for that.
我们可以使用段落和链接结束标记作为参考
So, for example this one,
比如这个
so we just wrote a regex_pattern and we are
我们写了一个 这样的正则表达
looking for the occurrence of these closing tags.
寻找这个结束标签的出现次数
Let's add NumParagraphs and NumLinks columns to our DataFrame.
我们把 NumParagraphs 和 NumLinks 列添加到 DataFrame 中
If you look at the head again,
如果再看一下头行
we can see that in both of these examples we have number of
这一行的 NumParagraphs 的值变成了 2
paragraphs of two and no links in these particular questions.
NumLinks 的值为 0
Then we've have numeric features.
现在我们有数值型的特征
For many models, we need to normalize their values
对于许多模型 我们需要标准化特征的值
to make sure that they span across the same range.
确保它们有相同的范围
After devising the distance function,
不然的话 距离函数会把
typically the feature with the highest values will dominate the results.
具有最高值的特征对结果的影响放大
Sparks ML library has several options such as normalizers standard scaler and MSQL.
Sparks ML 库有几个选项 例如 normalizers standard scaler 和 MSQL
All these functions require vector rows as an input.
所有这些函数都需要向量行作为输入
So, before we can use them,
所以 在我们使用这些函数之前
we need to convert our numeric columns to Sparks vector type.
需要将数值型数据转换为 Sparks 向量类型
We can use VectorAssembler from the Spark ML feature library.
我们可以使用 Spark ML feature 库中的 VectorAssembler
I'll show you the effect of using normalizer and standard
我会给你看看 StandardScaler 和 Normalizer
scalar on the vector of our current three features,
用在这三个特征上的效果
BodyLength, NumParagraphs and NumLinks.
BodyLength NumParagraphs 和 NumLinks
As we can see in this first record,
正如我们在第一条记录中看到的
Num features is now a DenseVector of these trigonometric values.
NumFeatures 现在是一个包含这三个值的 DenseVector
So, the number of words in the question,
问题中的单词数
the number of paragraphs and number of links.
段落数以及链接数
So, let's see what happens if we use normalizer.
接下来我们看看使用 normalizer 会发生什么
Normalizer is a transformer which transforms a dataset or vector rows,
Normalizer 可以对数据集或向量行进行转化
normalizing each vector to have unit norm.
把每个向量归一化
So, as you can see here,
正如你在这里看到的
normalizer kept the ratio of these values and now they sum up to one.
normalizer 会保持这些值的比率 现在它们总和为1
Standard scaler normalizes each feature to have unit standard deviation and and a 0 mean,
StandardScaler 将特征标准化为单位标准差是0均值 也可以是0均值单位标准差
depending on the value of the bit standard and bit mean.
取决于参数 withStd 和 withMean 的值
Once we take a look at the first few rows,
我们看了前几行之后
you can clearly see the difference.
你可以清楚地看到差异
For example, in the first checkered,
例如 在第一个纪录里
scaledNumFeatures were these, as we saw it before.
scaledNumFeatures 长这样 我们之前已经看到过了
After using the standard scalar,
使用 StandardScaler 后
we get a result of this,
我们得到了这个结果
and then another example in the second row.
这是第二行的例子